{
	"subject": "chemistry",
	"lesson": "l02",
	"grade": "c8",
	"quests": [{
		"id": 1,
		"question": "Burning of paper is a __________ change. ",
		"options": {
			"a": "physical",
			"b": "chemical",
			"c": "physical and chemical",
			"d": "neutral"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 2,
		"question": "Burning of matchstick is an example for chemical reaction caused by __________ ",
		"options": {
			"a": "contact in physical states",
			"b": "electricity",
			"c": "light",
			"d": "catalyst"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}, {
		"id": 3,
		"question": "__________ undergoes rusting. ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Tin",
			"b": "Sodium",
			"c": "Copper",
			"d": "Iron"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 4,
		"question": "The pigment responsible for browning of apples is __________. ",
		"options": {
			"a": "hydrated iron (II) oxide",
			"b": "melanin",
			"c": "starch",
			"d": "ozone"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 5,
		"question": "Brine is a concentrated solution of _____.",
		"options": {
			"a": "sodium sulphate",
			"b": "sodium chloride",
			"c": "calcium chloride",
			"d": "sodium bromide"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 6,
		"question": "Limestone contains __________ mainly ",
		"options": {
			"a": "calcium chloride",
			"b": "calcium carbonate",
			"c": "calcium nitrate",
			"d": "calcium sulphate"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 7,
		"question": "Which of the following factor induces electrtolysis? ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Heat",
			"b": "Light",
			"c": "Electricity",
			"d": "Catalysis"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 8,
		"question": "In Haber’s process of producing ammonia __________ is used as a catalyst.",
		"options": {
			"a": "nitrogen",
			"b": "hydrogen",
			"c": "iron",
			"d": "nickel"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 9,
		"question": "Dissolved gases like sulphur dioxide and nitrogen oxides in rain water causes __________ ",
		"options": {
			"a": "acid rain",
			"b": "base rain",
			"c": "heavy rain",
			"d": "neutral rain"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}, {
		"id": 10,
		"question": "__________ is/are responsible for global warming.",
		"options": {
			"a": "Carbon dioxide",
			"b": "Methane",
			"c": "Chlorofluorocarbons",
			"d": "Carbon dioxide, Methane, Chlorofluorocarbons"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 11,
		"question": "Photosynthesis ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Rusting",
			"b": "Electrolysis",
			"c": "Thermolysis",
			"d": "Food"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 12,
		"question": "Haber’s process ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Rusting",
			"b": "Electrolysis",
			"c": "Thermolysis",
			"d": "Catalysis"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 13,
		"question": "Iron ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Rusting",
			"b": "Electrolysis",
			"c": "Thermolysis",
			"d": "Catalysis"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}, {
		"id": 14,
		"question": "Decomposition ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Spoilage",
			"b": "Calcium oxide",
			"c": "Thermolysis",
			"d": "Tarnishing"
		},
		"answer": "b"
	}, {
		"id": 15,
		"question": "Biocatalyst ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Spoilage",
			"b": "Calcium oxide",
			"c": "Yeast",
			"d": "Tarnishing"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 16,
		"question": "Oxygen ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Spoilage",
			"b": "Calcium oxide",
			"c": "Ozone",
			"d": "Tarnishing"
		},
		"answer": "c"
	}, {
		"id": 17,
		"question": "Chemical reaction",
		"options": {
			"a": "Spoilage",
			"b": "Calcium oxide",
			"c": "Ozone",
			"d": "Tarnishing"
		},
		"answer": "d"
	}, {
		"id": 18,
		"question": "Food ",
		"options": {
			"a": "Spoilage",
			"b": "Calcium oxide",
			"c": "Ozone",
			"d": "Tarnishing"
		},
		"answer": "a"
	}]
}